[A Splendid Match]
[مباراة رائعة]
[Episode 31]
[الحلقة 31]
You are slandering me!
أنت تشوه سمعتي!
Master!
يتقن!
Drag him out.
اسحبه للخارج.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
You...
أنت...
I will report this to His Majesty!
سأبلغ جلالته بهذا الأمر!
Move.
يتحرك.
[Xianke Pavilion]
[جناح شيانكي]
Hurry up.
أسرع.
Let go of me!
اتركني!
[Identity Verified: An Deyu, Investigating Censor of the Censorate]
[تم التحقق من الهوية: آن ديو، المحقق في الرقابة]
To the next house.
إلى المنزل المجاور.
My Lord,
يا سيدي،
we've arrested quite a few today.
لقد ألقينا القبض على عدد لا بأس به اليوم.
Do you want to
هل تريد أن
go back and rest for a bit?
هل تعود وتستريح قليلاً؟
No time to rest.
لا وقت للراحة.
This bird's nest is excellent.
عش الطائر هذا ممتاز.
Have you heard
هل سمعت؟
about Ye Xian?
ماذا عن يي شيان؟
Yes, I have.
نعم، لقد فعلت.
His Majesty has transferred
قام جلالته بنقل
all cases related to the Inner Court
جميع القضايا المتعلقة بالمحكمة الداخلية
to the Xuanfeng Guard.
إلى حرس Xuanfeng.
They've arrested several imperial censors in a row,
لقد اعتقلوا العديد من مراقبي الإمبراطورية على التوالي،
all of whom had previously
جميعهم كانوا سابقاً
impeached the Marquis Changxing.
عزل الماركيز تشانغشينغ.
I also heard
سمعت أيضًا
he was always frail.
كان دائماً ضعيف البنية.
Just climbing a mountain
مجرد تسلق جبل
would cost him
سيكلفه ذلك
half his life.
نصف عمره.
How is it that when handling cases,
كيف يتم ذلك عند التعامل مع القضايا،
he is so ruthless?
هل هو بهذه القسوة؟
Isn't it because
أليس ذلك بسبب
his beloved one
حبيبته
was taken away from him?
هل أُخذ منه؟
Speaking of which, I'm quite curious.
وبالمناسبة، أنا فضولي للغاية.
Although Madam Chen isn't from a noble family,
على الرغم من أن السيدة تشين ليست من عائلة نبيلة،
the Gu family
عائلة غو
is still a family of scholars.
لا تزال عائلة من العلماء.
How did you manage to lure
كيف تمكنت من جذب...
both Chen and Ye at the same time?
هل كان كل من تشين ويي في نفس الوقت؟
Especially Chen,
وخاصة تشين،
who even went so far as to
بل إن الأمر وصل إلى حد...
reject the match proposed by Madam Fu.
رفض المباراة التي اقترحتها السيدة فو.
Madam Wang,
السيدة وانغ،
are you saying Madam Fu
هل تقصدين السيدة فو؟
once arranged a match for my husband?
هل سبق أن رتبت زواجاً لزوجي؟
Didn't you know?
ألم تكن تعلم؟
No, I didn't.
لا، لم أفعل.
I only know that
كل ما أعرفه هو ذلك
my husband
زوجي
invited the Senior Grand Secretary
تمت دعوة كبير أمناء السر
and Madam Fu to officiate our wedding.
والسيدة فو لتتولى عقد قراننا.
Since Madam Fu
منذ السيدة فو
was willing to officiate,
كان على استعداد لتولي مهمة التحكيم،
it's clear that the matter of matchmaking
من الواضح أن مسألة التوفيق بين الأزواج
is long in the past.
لقد مضى على ذلك زمن طويل.
As for you, Madam Wang,
أما أنتِ يا سيدتي وانغ،
my husband and I
أنا وزوجي
have been married for quite some time,
متزوجان منذ فترة طويلة،
but you specifically
لكن أنت تحديدا
bring this up today.
اطرح هذا الموضوع اليوم.
Those who know you
أولئك الذين يعرفونك
might think you're just making small talk.
قد يظن البعض أنك تتبادل أطراف الحديث فقط.
But those who don't
أما أولئك الذين لا يفعلون ذلك
might think you are
قد تظن أنك كذلك
deliberately disrespecting Madam Fu,
عدم احترام السيدة فو عمداً،
trying to sow discord
محاولة زرع الفتنة
between Madam Fu and me.
بيني وبين السيدة فو.
Don't slander me.
لا تشتموني.
Enough.
كافٍ.
That's not what I meant.
لم يكن هذا ما قصدته.
Madam Chen is right.
السيدة تشين محقة.
It's just a trivial matter.
إنها مسألة تافهة.
I've long forgotten it.
لقد نسيته منذ زمن طويل.
We are here today
نحن هنا اليوم
to taste tea and relax.
لتذوق الشاي والاسترخاء.
There's no need to mention the trivial details.
لا داعي لذكر التفاصيل التافهة.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
The pastries today
المعجنات اليوم
are truly excellent.
إنها ممتازة حقاً.
Yes,
نعم،
especially this blood bird's nest.
وخاصة عش طائر الدم هذا.
It's smooth and delicate,
إنه ناعم ورقيق،
very delicious.
لذيذ جداً.
But its appearance
لكن مظهره
looks somewhat like the tribute
يبدو إلى حد ما وكأنه تكريم
sent from Nanyang some time ago.
أُرسلت من نانيانغ منذ بعض الوقت.
What...
ماذا...
How could this be a tribute?
كيف يمكن أن يكون هذا تكريماً؟
You must be mistaken.
لا بد أنك مخطئ.
I picked up some random pieces
لقد التقطت بعض القطع العشوائية
of bird's nest from a shop.
من عش طائر من متجر.
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
Earlier, someone
في وقت سابق، شخص ما
brought top-grade blood bird's nest
أحضر عش طائر الدم عالي الجودة
to my shop for consignment,
إلى متجري للبيع بالعمولة،
claiming it was surplus tribute.
زاعمين أنها فائضة عن الحاجة.
I saw that
لقد رأيت ذلك
in person.
شخصياً.
The appearance
المظهر
is the same as
هو نفسه
the blood bird's nest you served.
عش طائر الدم الذي خدمته.
But at that time, I was worried,
لكن في ذلك الوقت، كنت قلقاً.
so I didn't dare accept them.
لذلك لم أجرؤ على قبولهم.
Madam Wang,
السيدة وانغ،
you should also
ينبغي عليك أيضاً
be more careful.
كن أكثر حذرا.
Make absolutely sure you aren't mistaken.
تأكد تماماً من أنك لست مخطئاً.
If it really is a tribute,
إذا كان ذلك حقاً تكريماً،
that would be bad.
سيكون ذلك سيئاً.
I...
أنا...
This...
هذا...
Has the Court underpaid
هل المحكمة تدفع أجراً أقل من المستحق؟
the Wang family?
عائلة وانغ؟
To think you would embezzle such things!
يا للعجب! كيف يُعقل أن تختلس مثل هذه الأشياء!
No...
لا...
Enough.
كافٍ.
Let's treat this as an accident.
لنعتبر هذا حادثاً عرضياً.
After everyone goes back,
بعد عودة الجميع،
please do not cause any further trouble.
من فضلك لا تسبب أي مشاكل أخرى.
Madam,
سيدتي،
Lord Chen has arrived.
لقد وصل اللورد تشين.
He says he is here to pick up Madam Chen.
يقول إنه هنا ليصطحب السيدة تشين.
Then I shall take my leave.
ثم سأغادر.
Tribute?
تكريم؟
I didn't want to expose her at first,
لم أكن أرغب في فضحها في البداية،
but this Madam Wang
لكن هذه السيدة وانغ
has repeatedly
وقد كرر ذلك مراراً وتكرارا
made things difficult for me.
لقد جعل الأمر صعباً بالنسبة لي.
Naturally, I won't indulge her anymore.
بطبيعة الحال، لن أسمح لها بالتصرف بهذه الطريقة بعد الآن.
I absolutely did not see it wrong.
لم أرَ ذلك خطأً على الإطلاق.
That was the tribute sent from Nanyang.
كان ذلك بمثابة التكريم الذي أرسلته نانيانغ.
You've been wronged.
لقد تعرضت للظلم.
So wronged.
لقد ظُلِموا كثيراً.
You shouldn't indulge her.
لا ينبغي عليك أن تدللها.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
I was thinking,
كنت أفكر،
with so many state affairs,
مع وجود العديد من شؤون الدولة،
from land reform down to tributes,
من إصلاح الأراضي وصولاً إلى الجزية،
they are riddled with holes
إنها مليئة بالثقوب
and flaws everywhere.
وعيوب في كل مكان.
Wang Xuanfan made one careless mistake,
ارتكب وانغ شوانفان خطأً واحداً نتيجة إهماله،
and you actually caught his weakness.
وقد اكتشفت بالفعل نقطة ضعفه.
Just watch.
شاهد فقط.
This time,
هذه المرة،
he has crossed my mentor's bottom line.
لقد تجاوز الخطوط الحمراء التي وضعها مرشدي.
He will fly into a rage.
سينفجر غضباً.
[Wang Residence]
[مقر إقامة وانغ]
Idiot!
غبي!
What an absolute idiot!
يا له من أحمق!
[Integrity, Prudence, Diligence, Harmony]
[النزاهة، الحكمة، الاجتهاد، الانسجام]
You...
أنت...
What were you thinking?
بماذا كنت تفكر؟
What were you thinking
ماذا كنت تفكر؟
using blood bird's nest to entertain them?
هل تستخدم عش طائر الدم لتسليتهم؟
Are you
أنت
tired of being a Grand Secretary's wife?
هل سئمتِ من كونكِ زوجة سكرتير كبير؟
You're pushing me into a fire pit!
أنت تدفعني إلى حفرة نار!
How was I supposed to know?
كيف كان من المفترض أن أعرف؟
It's boiled and put in a bowl,
يُسلق ويُوضع في وعاء،
yet she could still
ومع ذلك لا يزال بإمكانها
know that it's a tribute.
اعلم أن هذا تكريم.
That Gu Jinzhao,
أن قو جينزهاو ،
what is her tongue made of?
مم يتكون لسانها؟
How could she taste that?
كيف استطاعت أن تتذوق ذلك؟
She comes from a wealthy family.
هي تنتمي إلى عائلة ثرية.
What hasn't she eaten?
ما الذي لم تأكله؟
All you do
كل ما تفعله
is look down on merchants.
ينظرون بازدراء إلى التجار.
She's eaten more salt
لقد تناولت المزيد من الملح
than you've eaten rice!
أكثر مما أكلت من الأرز!
I look down on merchants?
هل أنظر إلى التجار بازدراء؟
Do you respect them?
هل تحترمهم؟
I respect no one,
لا أحترم أحداً،
but I respect wealth.
لكنني أحترم الثروة.
You...
أنت...
You must
يجب عليك أن
retrieve the consigned tributes
استعادة الجزية المودعة
immediately.
في الحال.
Is it really that serious?
هل الأمر بهذه الخطورة حقاً؟
Madam Fu already said
لقد قالت السيدة فو بالفعل
this was just an accident,
كان هذا مجرد حادث،
and told everyone
وأخبر الجميع
not to cause further trouble.
عدم التسبب في المزيد من المشاكل.
She was just paying lip service,
كانت تتظاهر فقط،
and you actually believed her?
وهل صدقتها فعلاً؟
Over the years, she and the Senior Grand Secretary
على مر السنين، هي وكبيرة السكرتيرين
have played good cop, bad cop.
لعب دور الشرطي الطيب والشرطي السيئ.
Have you still not figured that out?
ألم تكتشف ذلك بعد؟
I was just recently involved
لقد شاركت مؤخراً
in the scholars' riot,
في تمرد العلماء،
which offended the Senior Grand Secretary.
الأمر الذي أغضب كبير أمناء السر.
I was counting on you
كنت أعتمد عليك
to coax his wife,
لإقناع زوجته،
so Madam Fu could use some pillow talk.
لذا، قد تحتاج السيدة فو إلى بعض الأحاديث الرومانسية.
But instead,
لكن بدلاً من ذلك،
you drop this disaster on me.
أنت تُلقي عليّ بهذه الكارثة.
Are you God's punishment
هل أنت عقاب الله؟
for me?
لي؟
I'm your punishment?
أنا عقابك؟
Wang Xuanfan,
وانغ شوانفان
you better explain yourself.
من الأفضل أن تشرح نفسك.
Even the money for you to travel to the capital for the exams
حتى المال اللازم لسفرك إلى العاصمة لإجراء الامتحانات
was provided by my family.
تم توفيرها من قبل عائلتي.
Without me,
بدوني،
would you be where you are today?
هل كنت ستكون حيث أنت اليوم؟
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
When you needed me,
عندما احتجت إليّ،
I was your darling.
كنت حبيبتك.
Now that you don't,
الآن وقد توقفت عن ذلك،
I'm your punishment!
أنا عقابك!
And you call yourself a Grand Secretary?
وتسمي نفسك سكرتيراً عاماً؟
How can you be so shameless?
كيف يمكنك أن تكون بهذه الوقاحة؟
You are nothing but a village boor!
أنت لست سوى فظّ قروي!
Alright, alright.
حسناً، حسناً.
Calm down. Don't be angry.
اهدأ. لا تغضب.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Look, here's the plan.
انظر، هذه هي الخطة.
Right now,
الآن،
go immediately and
اذهب فوراً و
clean up all the loose ends regarding the tributes.
تنظيف جميع الأمور العالقة المتعلقة بالجوائز.
I'll make another trip
سأقوم برحلة أخرى
to the Senior Grand Secretary's residence.
إلى مقر إقامة كبير أمناء السر.
What for?
لماذا؟
What else?
ماذا بعد؟
To admit my mistake.
أن أعترف بخطئي.
[Integrity, Prudence, Diligence, Harmony]
[النزاهة، الحكمة، الاجتهاد، الانسجام]
Chen and his wife
تشين وزوجته
are really so annoying.
إنها مزعجة للغاية.
Does Lord Wang
هل يفعل اللورد وانغ ذلك؟
admire an official
الإعجاب بمسؤول
named Zeng Ruoyu?
اسمه تسنغ Ruoyu؟
Lord Zeng is the Chancellor of the National Academy.
اللورد زينغ هو رئيس الأكاديمية الوطنية.
He is Wang's fellow townsman.
هو من أبناء البلدة الذين يسكنهم وانغ.
Why do you bring him up?
لماذا تذكره؟
I know
أنا أعرف
Wang wants to recommend Lord Zeng
يرغب وانغ في التوصية باللورد تشنغ
to become the Vice Minister of Rites.
ليصبح نائب وزير المراسم.
And Lord Yao
والسيد ياو
even promised to vote for him.
بل ووعدت بالتصويت له.
How do you know this?
كيف عرفت ذلك؟
I also know
أعرف أيضاً
Grand Secretary Shen
السكرتير الأعظم شين
was reprimanded by the Senior Grand Secretary.
تلقى توبيخاً من كبير أمناء السر.
That was last month.
كان ذلك الشهر الماضي.
Where did you hear all this from?
من أين سمعت كل هذا؟
The tea party?
حفلة الشاي؟
I thought these madams
ظننت أن هؤلاء السيدات
would chat about things like
كنا نتحدث عن أشياء مثل
the Classic for Girls or whatever
الكلاسيكية للبنات أو ما شابه
at tea parties.
في حفلات الشاي.
I never expected
لم أتوقع ذلك أبداً
that what they discussed
هذا ما ناقشوه
were entirely court affairs.
كانت شؤوناً قضائية بحتة.
And I even saw
بل ورأيت
Madam Fu comforting Madam Shen, saying
السيدة فو تواسي السيدة شين قائلةً
that the Senior Grand Secretary
أن كبير أمناء السر
still trusts Grand Secretary Shen,
لا يزال يثق بالسكرتير العام شين،
telling her not to worry.
أخبرها ألا تقلق.
So it turns out the tea party
وهكذا اتضح أن حفلة الشاي
has this kind of function.
له هذا النوع من الوظائف.
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام.
Yes.
نعم.
I think it's even more interesting
أعتقد أن الأمر أكثر إثارة للاهتمام.
than doing business.
من ممارسة الأعمال التجارية.
Each madam sitting there
كل سيدة تجلس هناك
is practically a Grand Secretary herself.
هي عملياً بمثابة سكرتيرة كبرى.
A Madam Secretariat.
أمانة سرّية.
How can you say that?
كيف يمكنك قول ذلك؟
That's treasonous, Lord Chen.
هذا خيانة عظمى يا سيد تشين.
I know you like the tea party,
أعلم أنك تحب حفلات الشاي،
but do you know
لكن هل تعلم؟
if the term Madam Secretariat
إذا كان مصطلح "سيدة السكرتارية"
reaches the ears of the imperial censors,
تصل إلى مسامع الرقابة الإمبراطورية،
what would happen?
ماذا سيحدث؟
You don't want me to go again?
ألا تريدني أن أذهب مرة أخرى؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
I'm just reminding you
أنا فقط أذكرك
to be careful.
أن نكون حذرين.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Besides, I've already asked around.
إضافة إلى ذلك، لقد سألت بالفعل بعض الأشخاص.
The tea parties started several years ago
بدأت حفلات الشاي قبل عدة سنوات
and have been going on ever since.
واستمر هذا الوضع منذ ذلك الحين.
Moreover, these Grand Secretaries
علاوة على ذلك، هؤلاء الأمناء الكبار
use their wives
يستغلون زوجاتهم
to exchange information with each other.
لتبادل المعلومات فيما بينهم.
You've been following Senior Grand Secretary
لقد كنت تتابع كبير أمناء السر
for so many years,
لسنوات عديدة،
yet you didn't know about the tea parties.
لكنك لم تكن تعلم بأمر حفلات الشاي.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
It's a huge loss for me.
إنها خسارة فادحة بالنسبة لي.
Luckily, I found out today.
لحسن الحظ، اكتشفت ذلك اليوم.
That's why
لهذا السبب
I was so eager to marry you.
كنتُ أتوق بشدة للزواج منك.
Gu Jinzhao.
قو جينزهاو.
Look at my lips.
انظر إلى شفتي.
I need to go to Linxia Restaurant tomorrow.
أحتاج للذهاب إلى مطعم لينشيا غداً.
Third Uncle.
العم الثالث.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
It's about those scholars.
الأمر يتعلق بهؤلاء العلماء.
I heard some rumors
سمعت بعض الشائعات
that might be disadvantageous to you.
قد يكون ذلك غير مفيد لك.
I'll be right back.
سأعود حالاً.
You go inside first.
ادخل إلى الداخل أولاً.
Follow me.
اتبعني.
My Lady.
سيدتي.
This...
هذا...
Throw this away,
تخلص من هذا،
far away.
بعيداً.
The farther, the better.
كلما كانت المسافة أبعد، كان ذلك أفضل.
Yes.
نعم.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Did someone plead for leniency?
هل توسل أحدهم طلباً للرأفة؟
Yes.
نعم.
I dare not hide it from you, Third Uncle.
لا أجرؤ على إخفاء ذلك عنك يا عمي الثالث.
Indeed, the families
في الواقع، العائلات
and teachers of some scholars came to me,
وجاء إليّ معلمو بعض العلماء،
but I turned them all away.
لكنني رفضت استقبالهم جميعاً.
However,
لكن،
I've also heard some rumors outside.
سمعت أيضاً بعض الشائعات في الخارج.
They say you disregard the Court's laws
يقولون إنك تتجاهل قوانين المحكمة
and detain those scholars
واحتجاز هؤلاء العلماء
in the Shuntian Prefecture
في محافظة شونتيان
just to vent your personal anger.
لمجرد التنفيس عن غضبك الشخصي.
Personal anger?
غضب شخصي؟
Even if it is,
حتى لو كان الأمر كذلك،
it's not entirely wrong.
ليس الأمر خاطئاً تماماً.
I'm afraid imperial censors might impeach you.
أخشى أن يقوم الرقيب الإمبراطوري بعزلك.
So you came to me
إذن أتيت إلي
to ask me
أن تسألني
to release those scholars?
إطلاق سراح هؤلاء العلماء؟
You are perceptive, Third Uncle.
أنت فطن يا عمي الثالث.
The reason those scholars
السبب الذي دفع هؤلاء العلماء إلى ذلك
did such a thing was entirely
فعل مثل هذا الشيء كان بالكامل
out of a moment of righteous indignation.
انطلاقاً من لحظة غضب مُبرَّر.
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Just the fact that they could precisely
مجرد حقيقة أنهم يستطيعون تحديداً
block my carriage on the road
عرقل عربتي على الطريق
shows it wasn't just pure impulse,
يُظهر ذلك أنه لم يكن مجرد دافع لحظي،
not to mention
ناهيك عن
those flags and banners.
تلك الأعلام والرايات.
If they hadn't prepared
لو لم يكونوا قد استعدوا
a day or two in advance,
قبل يوم أو يومين،
it would have been impossible.
كان ذلك مستحيلاً.
You jump to conclusions
أنت تتسرع في استخلاص النتائج
about things you haven't seen
عن أشياء لم ترها
with your own eyes.
بأم عينيك.
Are you being foolish,
هل أنت أحمق؟
or do you have ulterior motives?
أم أن لديك دوافع خفية؟
I was wrong.
كنت مخطئاً.
I shouldn't have easily believed
ما كان ينبغي لي أن أصدق بسهولة
their nonsense.
هراءهم.
Please forgive me, Third Uncle.
أرجو أن تسامحني يا عمي الثالث.
You are an ambitious person.
أنت شخص طموح.
But the greatest weakness for ambitious people
لكن أكبر نقطة ضعف لدى الأشخاص الطموحين
is having high aims but lacking the talent.
لديه طموحات عالية ولكنه يفتقر إلى الموهبة.
If you pick up the habit of being self-righteous
إذا اكتسبت عادة التظاهر بالتقوى والغرور
and believing every rumor you hear,
وتصديق كل شائعة تسمعها،
how can you enter the Cabinet in the future?
كيف يمكنك الانضمام إلى مجلس الوزراء في المستقبل؟
You won't even get your foot in the door.
لن تتمكن حتى من وضع قدمك في الباب.
Get up.
استيقظ.
You don't need to worry about this anymore.
لا داعي للقلق بشأن هذا الأمر بعد الآن.
If life in the Hanlin Academy
إذا كانت الحياة في أكاديمية هانلين
is far too idle for you,
إنه وقت فراغ لا يناسبك على الإطلاق.
you can think about your marriage.
يمكنك التفكير في زواجك.
The Yu family has urged us many times.
لقد حثتنا عائلة يو مرات عديدة.
Within this year,
خلال هذا العام،
we'll arrange the wedding for you and Wanxue.
سنرتب حفل الزفاف لك ولوانكسو.
Yes.
نعم.
Then I shall
ثم سأفعل
take my leave first.
استأذن أولاً.
You may go.
يمكنك الذهاب.
Xuanqing?
شوانكينغ؟
Third Master,
السيد الثالث،
what happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Xuanqing came to me just now.
جاءني شوانكينغ الآن.
He clearly wanted to plead
كان من الواضح أنه يريد أن يتوسل
for the scholars who blocked my sedan chair.
إلى العلماء الذين عرقلوا وصولي إلى محفة سيارتي.
But he seemed to have no idea
لكن يبدو أنه لم يكن لديه أدنى فكرة
how to speak for them.
كيف أتحدث نيابة عنهم؟
It felt more like a spur-of-the-moment decision.
بدا الأمر أشبه بقرار عفوي.
Enough about him.
كفى حديثًا عنه.
How is it?
كيف هذا؟
Wang Xuanfan's embezzlement of the tributes
اختلاس وانغ شوانفان للجزية
has been fully investigated.
تم إجراء تحقيق كامل.
Here.
هنا.
[To the Honorable Master]
[إلى الأستاذ الجليل]
Every year, the tributes from all regions
في كل عام، يتم تقديم التحيات من جميع المناطق
are first sent to the Wang residence.
يتم إرسالها أولاً إلى مقر إقامة عائلة وانغ.
The Wang family opened a store in the capital
افتتحت عائلة وانغ متجراً في العاصمة
to sell specialties from the south,
لبيع منتجات مميزة من الجنوب،
claiming to exclusively sell surplus tributes,
يدّعون أنهم يبيعون حصرياً فائض الجزية،
but they are the actual tributes.
لكنها هي التكريمات الحقيقية.
This man is incredibly audacious.
هذا الرجل جريء للغاية.
[My investigation of the tribute officials and escorts]
[تحقيقي في مسؤولي مراسم التكريم والمرافقين]
[confirms that upon the annual tributes' arrival in the capital,]
[يؤكد أنه عند وصول الجزية السنوية إلى العاصمة،]
Should we arrange for someone
هل ينبغي أن نرتب لشخص ما؟
[a portion must first be diverted to the Wang residence.]
[يجب أولاً تحويل جزء منها إلى مقر إقامة عائلة وانغ.]
[The ledger records tributes like Nanyang blood bird's nest and Fujian rock tea;]
[يسجل السجل هدايا مثل عش طائر الدم في نانيانغ وشاي الصخور في فوجيان؛]
[these transactions, when cross-checked with the imperial registry,]
[هذه المعاملات، عند التحقق منها مع السجل الإمبراطوري،]
[show exact matches in patterns and styles across many items.]
[عرض التطابقات التامة في الأنماط والأساليب عبر العديد من العناصر.]
to impeach him?
هل نعزله؟
Same as last time.
كما في المرة السابقة.
Just impeach him.
اعزلوه.
Don't be too aggressive,
لا تكن عدوانياً للغاية،
and don't pursue it relentlessly.
ولا تلاحقه بلا هوادة.
Understood.
مفهوم.
Just a light tap.
مجرد نقرة خفيفة.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
My mentor regards Wang Xuanfan
معلمي يرحب بـ Wang Xuanfan
as his right-hand man.
بصفته ذراعه الأيمن.
To get rid of him,
للتخلص منه،
we need to take slow, steady steps,
علينا أن نتخذ خطوات بطيئة وثابتة.
wearing him down bit by bit.
إضعافه تدريجياً.
In the disaster relief grain case,
في قضية الحبوب المخصصة للإغاثة من الكوارث،
Madam Wang
السيدة وانغ
took dividends from the grain merchants.
حصل على أرباح من تجار الحبوب.
That's one piece lost.
هذا يعني فقدان قطعة واحدة.
Wang Xuanfan incited the scholars to block my sedan chair,
حرض وانغ شوانفان العلماء على منع استخدام محفتي،
angering His Majesty
إغضاب جلالته
and disrupting the land reform.
وتعطيل إصلاح الأراضي.
That's three pieces lost.
هذا يعني فقدان ثلاث قطع.
Wang Xuanfan
وانغ شوانفان
embezzled tributes.
الجزية المختلسة.
That's another piece lost.
هذا جزء آخر مفقود.
It seems
يبدو
a couple more strikes are needed.
هناك حاجة إلى ضربتين إضافيتين.
Soon.
قريباً.
[Integrity, Prudence, Diligence, Harmony]
[النزاهة، الحكمة، الاجتهاد، الانسجام]
Get out!
اخرج!
Did I tell you to come in?
هل طلبت منك الدخول؟
You have no manners at all!
ليس لديك أي أدب على الإطلاق!
Please calm your anger, Yuanweng.
أرجوك اهدأ يا يوانوينغ.
Actually, the Senior Grand Secretary
في الواقع، كبير أمناء السر
treats you as one of his own,
يعاملك كواحد من أبنائه،
which is why he was so blunt.
ولهذا السبب كان صريحاً للغاية.
[Integrity, Prudence, Diligence, Harmony]
[النزاهة، الحكمة، الاجتهاد، الانسجام]
You call that blunt?
أتسمي هذا الكلام صريحاً؟
That was a slap in the face!
كان ذلك بمثابة صفعة على الوجه!
Slapping me time and time again!
يصفعني مراراً وتكراراً!
Last time it was in front of Third Mr. Chen,
في المرة الأخيرة كان ذلك أمام السيد الثالث تشين،
this time it was in front of His Majesty.
هذه المرة كان ذلك أمام جلالته.
Just because a few
لمجرد أن القليل
ignorant scholars shouted a few words
صرخ بعض العلماء الجهلة بكلمات قليلة
about liquidating the imperial estates,
بشأن تصفية ممتلكات الإمبراطورية،
he... he reprimanded me,
لقد وبخني،
saying I was acting out and told me to step down!
قالوا إنني أتصرف بشكل غير لائق وطلبوا مني الاستقالة!
Haven't I done enough
ألم أفعل ما يكفي؟
for land reform?
من أجل إصلاح الأراضي؟
I gave so much money
لقد تبرعت بالكثير من المال
to make up for it the moment he asked.
لتعويض ذلك في اللحظة التي طلب فيها ذلك.
Wasn't it all for him?
ألم يكن كل ذلك من أجله؟
Actually I don't blame
في الحقيقة، أنا لا ألوم أحداً.
the Senior Grand Secretary.
السكرتير العام الأقدم.
He had no choice.
لم يكن لديه خيار آخر.
He was put on the spot by Chen.
وضع تشين الرجل في موقف محرج.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
In this scholar riot,
في هذه الشغب الأكاديمي،
if Chen Yanyun truly
إذا كانت تشين يانيون حقاً
considered the bigger picture,
بالنظر إلى الصورة الأكبر،
he could have easily
كان بإمكانه بسهولة
covered the matter up right there.
لقد غطى الأمر هناك.
But instead,
لكن بدلاً من ذلك،
he sent the scholars and their banners
أرسل العلماء وراياتهم
straight to the Shuntian Prefecture.
مباشرة إلى محافظة شونتيان.
It's such a huge incident.
إنه حادث ضخم للغاية.
I couldn't keep it hidden either,
لم أستطع إخفاء الأمر أيضاً،
so I had to report it upwards.
لذلك كان عليّ إبلاغ المسؤولين.
Alright, alright.
حسناً، حسناً.
I'm not blaming you either.
أنا أيضاً لا ألومك.
[Integrity, Prudence, Diligence, Harmony]
[النزاهة، الحكمة، الاجتهاد، الانسجام]
I reflected carefully.
لقد فكرت ملياً.
If I'm not mistaken,
إن لم أكن مخطئاً،
ever since he took down Fan Chuan in the disaster relief grain case,
منذ أن أطاح بفان تشوان في قضية الحبوب المتعلقة بالإغاثة من الكوارث،
Chen had already
كان تشين قد فعل ذلك بالفعل
started targeting me.
بدأوا باستهدافي.
He resented me for making him
لقد استاء مني لأني جعلته
take the blame for the grain swap.
تحمل مسؤولية مبادلة الحبوب.
So narrow-minded.
ضيق الأفق هذا.
We've been talking for so long.
لقد تحدثنا لفترة طويلة.
I'm getting tired.
أشعر بالتعب.
Then we shall take our leave.
ثم نغادر.
Hold on, Ziliang.
انتظر يا زيليانغ.
I have something to ask you.
لدي سؤال أريد أن أسألك إياه.
I remember Gu Deyuan, the Censorate's
أتذكر غو ديوان، من مكتب الرقابة
Assistant Censor-in-Chief,
مساعد رئيس الرقابة،
was previously involved in
كان يشارك سابقاً في
the embezzlement case of Zeng Yanqiu, the Vice Minister of Works.
قضية اختلاس الأموال الخاصة بـ تشنغ يانكيو، نائب وزير الأشغال.
Later, it was left unresolved.
وفي وقت لاحق، تُرك الأمر دون حل.
A person used to taking bribes
شخص معتاد على تلقي الرشاوى
can never restrain themselves.
لا يستطيعون كبح جماح أنفسهم أبداً.
Now that he has become in-laws with Chen,
والآن بعد أن أصبح صهراً مع تشين،
with such a big backer,
بوجود داعم كبير كهذا،
I think he's going to make a move again.
أعتقد أنه سيقوم بخطوة أخرى.
Yes.
نعم.
However,
لكن،
why didn't you hand this over to Lord Yao?
لماذا لم تسلم هذا إلى اللورد ياو؟
Wouldn't it be more convenient
ألن يكون ذلك أكثر ملاءمة؟
for the Ministry of Justice to investigate this?
هل ينبغي على وزارة العدل التحقيق في هذا الأمر؟
Gu Deyuan's daughter
ابنة قو ديوان
is married to Yao Ping's youngest son.
متزوجة من الابن الأصغر لياو بينغ.
Zhao,
تشاو،
we've selected a few varieties
لقد اخترنا بعض الأنواع
of newly released tea.
من أنواع الشاي التي تم طرحها حديثاً.
We can't quite make up our minds,
لا نستطيع أن نحسم أمرنا تماماً،
so we'd like you to take a look.
لذا نود منك إلقاء نظرة.
Lan,
و،
preparing for the Linxia Restaurant
الاستعداد لمطعم لينشيا
involves a lot of trivial matters.
يتضمن الكثير من الأمور التافهة.
Thanks for your hard work.
شكراً لجهودكم المبذولة.
[Snow Orchid Breaths on Jade] [Twilight Lotus Diffuses Scent]
[أزهار الأوركيد الثلجية تتنفس على اليشم] [زهرة اللوتس الشفقية تنشر العطر]
During my home visit this time,
خلال زيارتي المنزلية هذه المرة،
I didn't go back to Daxin.
لم أعد إلى داكسين.
Did they make things difficult for you?
هل جعلوا الأمور صعبة عليك؟
It was alright, actually.
كان الأمر جيداً في الواقع.
Grandmother didn't even bring it up.
لم تذكر الجدة الموضوع حتى.
Second Aunt and Lian
العمة الثانية وليان
made a few remarks.
أدلى ببعض الملاحظات.
I didn't care about them at all.
لم أكن أهتم بهم على الإطلاق.
However,
لكن،
I do have a favor
لدي طلب.
to ask of you.
أن أطلب منك.
Go ahead.
تفضل.
I want to move back to Sili Hutong.
أريد العودة إلى سيلي هوتونغ.
Now that you've married into the Chen Mansion,
الآن وقد تزوجت من عائلة تشين مانشن،
Father has been assigned outside the capital,
تم نقل الأب إلى خارج العاصمة.
and Rong is always
ورونغ دائماً
at the Qifang Hutong Academy.
في أكاديمية تشيفانغ هوتونغ.
It's just me alone in the ancestral home,
أنا وحدي في منزل أجدادي،
which is quite boring.
وهذا ممل للغاية.
That is indeed an option.
هذا خيار مطروح بالفعل.
However, you need to think it through.
لكن عليك التفكير في الأمر ملياً.
After all, you are an
فأنت في النهاية...
unmarried lady.
سيدة غير متزوجة.
Setting up a household on your own
تأسيس أسرة بمفردك
will inevitably invite gossip.
سيؤدي ذلك حتماً إلى انتشار الشائعات.
I'm not afraid.
أنا لست خائفا.
I just want to live more freely,
أريد فقط أن أعيش بحرية أكبر،
which is better than anything else.
وهذا أفضل من أي شيء آخر.
Since you've thought it through,
بما أنك فكرت في الأمر جيداً،
then go ahead and move.
ثم انطلق وتحرك.
The property deed for Sili Hutong
سند ملكية سيلي هوتونغ
is with me.
هو معي.
You have a share.
لك حصة.
If you have spare money,
إذا كان لديك مال فائض،
I can sell my share to you too.
يمكنني بيع حصتي لك أيضاً.
Consider it as acquiring an estate.
اعتبر الأمر بمثابة اكتساب عقار.
That's wonderful!
هذا رائع!
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Sit down.
اجلس.
[Twilight Lotus Diffuses Scent ]
[زهرة اللوتس الشفقية تنشر العطر ]
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
do you still remember
هل ما زلت تتذكر؟
Mu Zhidi?
مو زيدي؟
The one who
الشخص الذي
looks a bit silly?
يبدو الأمر سخيفاً بعض الشيء؟
His father,
والده،
Lord Mu Shi'an,
اللورد مو شيان،
is a longtime friend of your brother-in-law.
هو صديق قديم لأخي زوجتك.
This time,
هذه المرة،
he brought it up again.
لقد أثار الموضوع مرة أخرى.
I told your brother-in-law
أخبرتُ صهرك
that when they brought it up the year before last,
أنه عندما أثاروا الموضوع في العام قبل الماضي،
you had already refused.
لقد رفضت بالفعل.
Your brother-in-law
صهرك
knows all of this.
يعلم كل هذا.
Then,
ثم،
what does he think?
ما رأيه؟
Your brother-in-law says
يقول صهرك
Mr. Mu
السيد مو
is a decent person,
هو شخص لائق،
and Mu family has a good reputation.
وتتمتع عائلة مو بسمعة طيبة.
However,
لكن،
marriage is a lifelong matter.
الزواج مسألة مدى الحياة.
You must think it through
يجب أن تفكر في الأمر جيداً
and don't force it.
ولا تجبره على ذلك.
Since my brother-in-law says so,
بما أن صهري يقول ذلك،
then,
ثم،
could you
يمكنك
arrange for Mu Zhidi and me
رتب الأمر لي ولمو زيدي
to meet?
لنلتقي؟
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Then I'll pick a suitable time
ثم سأختار الوقت المناسب
for you two to meet.
لكي تلتقيا أنتما الاثنان.
We'll talk more about it then.
سنتحدث عن ذلك بمزيد من التفصيل حينها.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
I heard
سمعت
Ye Xian has been acting like a madman,
يتصرف يي شيان كالمجنون،
angering quite a few court officials.
مما أثار غضب عدد كبير من مسؤولي المحكمة.
It's true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
[Ye Residence]
[مقر إقامته]
Pass it down to him?
هل يمكن نقلها إليه؟
Can he even swing it?
هل يستطيع حتى أن يتأرجح بها؟
Look at his frail physique,
انظر إلى بنيته الجسدية الهزيلة،
he can forget about wielding a sword in this lifetime!
عليه أن ينسى أمر حمل السيف في هذه الحياة!
Fu Hailian is absolutely determined
فو هايليان مصمم تماماً
to see me dead.
أن تراني ميتاً.
And you came in to accompany me?
ودخلتَ لترافقني؟
Do you think you're being a filial son?
هل تعتقد أنك ابن بار؟
Foolish!
غبي!
Figure out a way to get out of here.
ابحث عن طريقة للخروج من هنا.
Protect your mother and your sister.
احمِ والدتك وأختك.
If the Marquis's mansion is gone, so be it.
إذا اختفى قصر الماركيز، فليكن.
You never wanted
لم ترغب أبدًا
to inherit the title anyway.
ليرث اللقب على أي حال.
It's very kind of you to think of my lord,
لطف كبير منك أن تفكر في سيدي،
and even invite a renowned doctor.
بل وحتى دعوة طبيب مشهور.
It's just that lately,
الأمر فقط أنني في الآونة الأخيرة،
his temper has become more eccentric.
لقد أصبح مزاجه أكثر غرابة.
If he speaks harshly,
إذا تحدث بفظاظة،
please bear with him.
أرجوكم تحملوه.
Don't I know his temper well enough?
ألا أعرف طبعه جيداً؟
Don't worry about that.
لا تقلق بشأن ذلك.
My Lord, Miss Xue is here.
سيدي، الآنسة شو هنا.
She specially brought a renowned doctor.
لقد أحضرت طبيباً مشهوراً خصيصاً.
Ye Xian!
يي شيان!
My Lord!
يا إلهي!
Doctor,
طبيب،
My lord has already finished his medicine.
لقد انتهى سيدي من تناول دوائه بالفعل.
Why isn't he getting better?
لماذا لا يتحسن؟
What exactly is going on?
ما الذي يحدث بالضبط؟
Please speak frankly.
أرجو أن تتحدث بصراحة.
His chronic illness is hard to cure.
مرضه المزمن يصعب علاجه.
I'm afraid his life
أخشى على حياته
won't last much longer.
لن يدوم ذلك طويلاً.
What?
ماذا؟
Doctor,
طبيب،
I beg you, please save him!
أرجوكم، أنقذوه!
I'll kowtow to you, Doctor!
سأخضع لك يا دكتور!
Please get up quickly.
أرجو أن تنهض بسرعة.
-I beg you! -Doctor Zhou,
-أرجوك! -دكتور تشو،
if I ask you to treat him with all your might,
إذا طلبت منك أن تعامله بكل قوتك،
how long can he live?
كم من الوقت يمكنه أن يعيش؟
At most,
على الأكثر،
three years.
ثلاث سنوات.
Three years?
ثلاث سنوات؟
Don't cry here.
لا تبكِ هنا.
Ruixiang,
رويكسيانج،
take Doctor Zhou to write the prescription.
اصطحب الدكتور تشو لكتابة الوصفة الطبية.
Yes.
نعم.
You're awake?
هل أنت مستيقظ؟
Actually...
في الحقيقة...
actually, Doctor Zhou's
في الواقع، الدكتور تشو
prognosis might not be accurate.
قد لا يكون التشخيص دقيقاً.
We need to consult a few more doctors
نحتاج إلى استشارة عدد قليل من الأطباء الآخرين
to be certain.
للتأكد.
I heard there's an imperial physician in Songjiang Prefecture...
سمعت أن هناك طبيباً إمبراطورياً في محافظة سونغجيانغ...
Don't tell anyone.
لا تخبر أحداً.
The fact that I only have three years to live.
حقيقة أنني لم يتبق لي سوى ثلاث سنوات لأعيشها.
I hope you can keep it a secret for me.
أتمنى أن تتمكن من إبقاء الأمر سراً بالنسبة لي.
Didn't I just say?
ألم أقل ذلك للتو؟
What Doctor Zhou said
ما قاله الدكتور تشو
might not be accurate.
قد لا تكون دقيقة.
-He is right. -He...
- هو محق. - هو...
Three years
ثلاث سنوات
is enough.
يكفي.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Shut up.
اسكت.
Were you going to say it's none of my business?
هل كنت ستقول إن هذا ليس من شأني؟
I just saved your life,
لقد أنقذت حياتك للتو،
and you'd better have a conscience.
والأفضل أن يكون لديك ضمير.
I'm going to Zhending Prefecture.
سأذهب إلى محافظة زيندينغ.
For work?
للعمل؟
In your condition,
في حالتك،
how can you work?
كيف يمكنك العمل؟
Let me go with you.
دعني أذهب معك.
Didn't you say
ألم تقل
I should keep your secret?
هل يجب عليّ أن أحفظ سرّك؟
Then take me with you.
ثم خذني معك.
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
if I get drunk one day,
إذا سكرت يوماً ما،
and accidentally slip up,
ويرتكب خطأً غير مقصود،
I might just tell everyone.
ربما سأخبر الجميع.
You're back?
هل عدت؟
You're late today.
لقد تأخرت اليوم.
I had already finished my shift,
لقد انتهيت من ورديتي بالفعل،
but my mentor suddenly remembered the river project,
لكن مرشدي تذكر فجأة مشروع النهر،
and insisted on discussing it.
وأصر على مناقشته.
This discussion
هذه المناقشة
took four whole hours.
استغرق الأمر أربع ساعات كاملة.
Seeing you look like this
رؤيتك تبدو هكذا
reminds me
يذكرني
of an idiom.
من المصطلحات الاصطلاحية.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Standing by with folded arms.
يقفون مكتوفي الأيدي.
Listen to that,
استمع إلى ذلك،
someone is
شخص ما
complaining that I'm not a virtuous wife.
يشكون من أنني لست زوجة فاضلة.
Let me attend to Lord Chen right now.
دعوني أهتم بالسيد تشين الآن.
Let me serve you well.
دعني أخدمك جيداً.
-Lord Chen, -That's more like it.
-سيد تشين، -هذا أفضل.
please have a seat.
تفضل بالجلوس.
Let's see where you can run.
لنرى إلى أين يمكنك الركض.
What should we do?
ماذا ينبغي علينا أن نفعل؟
Yanyun didn't marry
لم تتزوج يانيون
a virtuous wife.
زوجة فاضلة.
You don't need to be virtuous.
لستَ بحاجة لأن تكون فاضلاً.
This is perfectly fine.
هذا جيد تماماً.
I like it.
أحبها.
Besides,
بجانب،
you have other strengths.
لديك نقاط قوة أخرى.
What?
ماذا؟
Guess.
يخمن.
You're rich.
أنت غني.
Hey.
يا.
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
Let me hold you a bit longer.
دعني أحتضنك لفترة أطول قليلاً.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Tired today?
هل تشعر بالتعب اليوم؟
I'm alright,
أنا بخير،
just need to hold you more.
أحتاج فقط إلى احتضانك أكثر.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
Mother fell ill today,
مرضت والدتي اليوم،
but she didn't call for a physician.
لكنها لم تستدع طبيباً.
Do you want to go take a look?
هل ترغب في إلقاء نظرة؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
I already told her the truth.
لقد أخبرتها بالحقيقة بالفعل.
No wonder.
لا عجب في ذلك.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
how could Yanwen
كيف يمكن ليانوين أن تفعل ذلك؟
do...
يفعل...
do
يفعل
such things?
مثل هذه الأشياء؟
Since he was little,
منذ صغره،
I hired renowned teachers for him,
لقد وظفت له معلمين مرموقين،
and gave him
وأعطاه
the exact same education
نفس التعليم بالضبط
like his brothers.
مثل إخوته.
You must not blame yourself.
لا يجب أن تلوم نفسك.
They say a dragon has nine sons,
يقولون إن للتنين تسعة أبناء،
and each one is uniquely different.
وكل واحد منها مختلف بشكل فريد.
If Fourth Master grew up astray,
إذا نشأ السيد الرابع ضلّ الطريق،
how could anyone blame you?
كيف يمكن لأحد أن يلومك؟
Besides,
بجانب،
if you ask around the entire capital,
إذا سألت في جميع أنحاء العاصمة،
no one raises the younger generations better than you do.
لا أحد يربي الأجيال الشابة أفضل منك.
Not to mention Third Master,
ناهيك عن السيد الثالث،
who is highly respected as a Grand Secretary.
الذي يحظى باحترام كبير بصفته سكرتيراً عاماً.
Second Master,
السيد الثاني،
is also a high-ranking provincial official.
وهو أيضاً مسؤول إقليمي رفيع المستوى .
And in the next generation,
وفي الجيل القادم،
Xuanqing,
شوانكينغ،
is a dignified Tanhua scholar.
هو عالمٌ مرموقٌ في مدرسة تانهوا.
In the future,
في المستقبل،
he might also become a Cabinet Minister.
وقد يصبح أيضاً وزيراً في الحكومة.
As long as you keep an open mind,
طالما أنك تحافظ على انفتاح ذهنك،
and don't dwell on a dead end,
ولا تستسلم للطريق المسدود،
your days
أيامك
will surely be harmonious and beautiful.
سيكون الأمر بالتأكيد متناغماً وجميلاً.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Actually,
في الحقيقة،
Mother had long suspected
لطالما كانت الأم تشك في ذلك
that he harmed Fifth Brother.
أنه ألحق الأذى بالأخ الخامس.
She just didn't want to believe it.
لم ترغب في تصديق ذلك.
Yesterday,
أمس،
when I told her
عندما أخبرتها
that he was the one who hired people
أنه هو من كان يوظف الناس
to kidnap you,
لاختطافك،
she understood everything.
لقد فهمت كل شيء.
She even asked
بل إنها سألت
if Fourth Brother
إذا كان الأخ الرابع
will never come back again.
لن أعود أبداً.
You don't need to worry.
لا داعي للقلق.
With Mother's personality,
بشخصية الأم،
in a couple of days,
في غضون يومين،
she'll be able to
ستكون قادرة على
step out decently again
اخرج بشكل لائق مرة أخرى
and be the respected matriarch.
وأن تكون الأم المحترمة.
Every family has its own difficulties.
كل عائلة تواجه صعوباتها الخاصة.
But in our family
لكن في عائلتنا
things are not difficult.
الأمور ليست صعبة.
[Gu Mansion]
[قصر غو]
[Moonlit Seclusion]
[عزلة تحت ضوء القمر]
[Blessings Passed Down for Generations]
[بركات تتوارثها الأجيال]
Zhao!
تشاو!
Lan,
و،
congratulations!
تهانينا!
[Snow from Yingzhong]
[ثلج من يينغتشونغ]
You move to your new home!
تنتقل إلى منزلك الجديد!
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Yanying was going to come too,
كانت يانينغ ستأتي أيضاً،
but for no reasons,
ولكن بدون أي سبب،
starting from today,
ابتداءً من اليوم،
she's been having an upset stomach.
إنها تعاني من اضطراب في المعدة.
Perhaps she was greedy last night,
ربما كانت جشعة الليلة الماضية،
and had too many cold things.
وكان لديه الكثير من الأشياء الباردة.
So as for her gift,
أما بالنسبة لهديتها،
she had to ask me to bring it to you.
كان عليها أن تطلب مني إحضاره إليك.
There will be many opportunities in the future.
ستكون هناك فرص كثيرة في المستقبل.
Next time I will send her another invitation.
سأرسل لها دعوة أخرى في المرة القادمة.
Where is Wanxue?
أين وانكسيو؟
She should be here soon.
ينبغي أن تصل إلى هنا قريباً.
[Blessings Passed Down for Generations]
[بركات تتوارثها الأجيال]
I'm here!
أنا هنا!
Just before leaving the house,
قبل مغادرة المنزل مباشرة،
my stepmother
زوجة أبي
suddenly asked about my embroidery.
سألني فجأة عن تطريزي.
If I hadn't prepared in advance,
لو لم أكن قد استعدت مسبقاً،
I fear I would have missed lunch today.
أخشى أنني كنت سأفوت وجبة الغداء اليوم.
Dear Lan,
عزيزتي لان،
congratulations on your new home.
ألف مبروك على منزلك الجديد.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
With her here,
بوجودها هنا،
it's definitely going to be fun.
سيكون الأمر ممتعاً بالتأكيد.
Is Mr. Mu
هل السيد مو
also coming today?
هل سيصل اليوم أيضاً؟
What are you afraid of?
ممّ تخاف؟
You are the head of the household now.
أنت رب الأسرة الآن.
He's coming over
سيأتي إلينا
to congratulate you on your new home too.
أهنئكم أيضاً على منزلكم الجديد.
You should
ينبغي عليك
greet him naturally.
استقبله بحفاوة.
Zhao, please come with me.
تشاو، أرجوك تعال معي.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
My Lady, Mr. Mu has arrived.
سيدتي، لقد وصل السيد مو.
Xuanqing!
شوانكينج!
[Harmony Brings Blessings]
[الانسجام يجلب البركات]
Mu Zhidi
مو زيدي
bowed about eighteen times already.
انحنى حوالي ثمانية عشر مرة بالفعل.
Poor thing.
يا حرام.
Since you invited him over,
بما أنك دعوته إلى منزلك،
you can't just not say a single word,
لا يمكنك ببساطة ألا تنطق بكلمة واحدة،
and ignore him like this, can you?
وتتجاهله هكذا، هل تستطيع؟
I...
أنا...
I don't know what to say.
لا أعرف ماذا أقول.
Wanxue,
وانكسو,
this is your first time in this residence?
هل هذه هي المرة الأولى التي تسكن فيها في هذا السكن؟
I'll show you around.
سأريك المكان.
Okay!
تمام!
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
I'll go for a walk too.
سأذهب في نزهة أيضًا.
Mr. Mu,
السيد مو،
how about
ماذا عن
we go for a walk too?
هل نذهب في نزهة أيضًا؟
Sure, sure.
بالتأكيد، بالتأكيد.
Mr. Mu,
السيد مو،
my inviting you here this time
دعوتكم إلى هنا هذه المرة
is actually not a genuine attempt at matchmaking.
في الواقع، هذه ليست محاولة جادة للتوفيق بين الأزواج.
Rather,
بدلاً من،
I didn't want to brush off my sister
لم أكن أريد أن أتجاهل أختي
and brother-in-law's good intentions.
ونوايا صهره الحسنة.
I have actually
لقد فعلت ذلك بالفعل
made up my mind
لقد اتخذت قراري
to never marry.
عدم الزواج مطلقا.
Why?
لماذا؟
You should know my situation.
يجب أن تعرف وضعي.
My father was demoted to Pingyang Prefecture,
تم نقل والدي إلى محافظة بينغيانغ،
and my mom made a mistake
وارتكبت أمي خطأً
and is still locked up to this day.
ولا يزال محتجزاً حتى يومنا هذا.
I also made many mistakes in the past.
لقد ارتكبت أيضاً العديد من الأخطاء في الماضي.
Thanks to my sister for forgiving my past misdeeds.
أشكر أختي على مسامحتها لي على أخطائي السابقة.
In short,
باختصار،
if I wanted to marry
لو أردت الزواج
someone of a higher status,
شخص ذو مكانة أعلى،
they wouldn't care for me,
لن يهتموا بي،
and I wouldn't force myself on them either.
ولن أفرض نفسي عليهم أيضاً.
If I settled for less,
لو رضيت بأقل من ذلك،
I wouldn't be happy.
لن أكون سعيداً.
It's better to be alone
من الأفضل أن تكون وحيداً
and live a peaceful life.
وعيش حياة هادئة.
Now,
الآن،
I just want to learn from my sister
أريد فقط أن أتعلم من أختي
how to do business properly,
كيفية إدارة الأعمال التجارية بشكل صحيح،
and save up more money.
وادخر المزيد من المال.
In the future,
في المستقبل،
when my mom grows old,
عندما تكبر أمي في السن،
I will beg Old Madam Ji
سأتوسل إلى السيدة العجوز جي
and bring her out so I can serve her well.
وأخرجها حتى أتمكن من خدمتها جيداً.
I would be content with that for my life.
سأكون راضياً بذلك طوال حياتي.
You...
أنت...
why aren't you saying anything?
لماذا لا تقول شيئاً؟
I...
أنا...
I am a clumsy speaker.
أنا متحدث أخرق.
You have been through so much.
لقد مررتِ بالكثير.
If I were in your shoes,
لو كنت مكانك،
I would be exactly the same,
سأكون مثلك تماماً.
only wanting to live on my own.
أرغب فقط في العيش بمفردي.
But I truly
لكنني حقاً
feel sorry for you.
أشعر بالأسف تجاهك.
So...
لذا...
so... so I really don't know
إذن... إذن أنا حقاً لا أعرف
what else to say.
ماذا عساي أن أقول أيضاً؟
I... I brought some people with me.
لقد أحضرت معي بعض الأشخاص.
They are waiting outside.
إنهم ينتظرون في الخارج.
Why did you bring people over?
لماذا أحضرت الناس؟
I wanted...
أردت...
to give you a pond of lucky fish.
ليمنحك بركة من الأسماك المحظوظة.
Give me a pond of lucky fish?
هل تريد بركة مليئة بالأسماك المحظوظة؟
A few days ago,
قبل بضعة أيام،
when I received your invitation,
عندما تلقيت دعوتك،
I went to find Rong.
ذهبت لأبحث عن رونغ.
I asked him
سألته
what exactly you like.
ما الذي يعجبك تحديداً؟
Rong said,
قال رونغ:
since you were pampered from a young age,
بما أنكِ كنتِ مدللة منذ صغركِ،
you lack nothing.
لا ينقصك شيء.
But after Madam Chen arrived in the capital,
لكن بعد وصول السيدة تشين إلى العاصمة،
your mother kept a pond of lucky fish
كانت والدتك تحتفظ ببركة من أسماك الحظ
in her courtyard,
في فناء منزلها،
which you admired for a long time.
الذي كنت معجبًا به لفترة طويلة.
So,
لذا،
I thought
ظننت
I would also build a pond
سأبني بركة أيضًا
in your courtyard,
في فناء منزلك،
and keep some lucky fish in it.
واحتفظ ببعض الأسماك المحظوظة فيه.
This way, when you have free time,
وبهذه الطريقة، عندما يكون لديك وقت فراغ،
you can watch the fish,
يمكنك مشاهدة الأسماك،
and your heart might feel a bit lighter.
وقد تشعر براحة أكبر في قلبك.
I...
أنا...
also called some craftsmen over.
كما تم استدعاء بعض الحرفيين.
Earlier, I was
في وقت سابق، كنت
afraid it would be too presumptuous
أخشى أن يكون ذلك متغطرسًا للغاية
and scare you,
ويخيفك،
so I...
لذا أنا...
didn't let them in.
لم يسمح لهم بالدخول.
You went through a lot of trouble.
لقد تحملت الكثير من المتاعب.
Then...
ثم...
let them come in.
دعهم يدخلون.
Sure!
بالتأكيد!
But...
لكن...
Let me lead the way.
دعني أقود الطريق.
Okay.
تمام.
Is Lord Chen treating you well?
هل يعاملك اللورد تشين معاملة حسنة؟
Yes.
نعم.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
I am truly happy for you.
أنا سعيد حقاً لأجلك.
I was quite nervous
كنت متوتراً للغاية
about getting married.
عن الزواج.
But the moment I think about
لكن في اللحظة التي أفكر فيها
you being in the Chen family,
كونك من عائلة تشين،
I don't worry as much.
لم أعد أشعر بالقلق كثيراً.
Wanxue,
وانكسو,
are you very fond of Xuanqing?
هل أنت مولع جداً بشوانكينغ؟
But
لكن
I don't know his feelings.
لا أعرف مشاعره.
Why would you say that?
لماذا تقول ذلك؟
You don't know.
أنت لا تعلم.
After he returned to the capital,
بعد عودته إلى العاصمة،
he has only been to my house once.
لم يزر منزلي إلا مرة واحدة.
He only spoke to my father,
لم يتحدث إلا مع والدي،
and as for me,
أما أنا،
he spoke less than two sentences
لقد نطق بأقل من جملتين
before leaving.
قبل المغادرة.
Wanxue,
وانكسو,
Third Aunt.
العمة الثالثة.
[A Splendid Match]
[مباراة رائعة]